- [Voiceover] We've spent so much trying
to basically make sure we have an exact
vector replica of the original drawing.
Why even bother?
If we already have the original drawing,
why are we working so hard to turn it into vectors?
And the most straightforward answer is,
not only have we managed to correct the art,
because recall that it used to be a pretty dismal scan
in the first place, but the ultimate reason
for converting it to vectors is so we can
scale the artwork to any size we like.
And so let me show you how that works.
I'll go ahead and press Control + 0
or Command + 0 on a Mac to zoom out,
and I'm gonna switch to the Artwork tool.
Once again, you can get that by pressing Shift + O,
and up here in the control panel I'm gonna click
inside the W value there and I'm just gonna enter
*10 in order to multiply it times 10,
so we go up to 4320 points, and then
I'm gonna do the same with the height value,
I'll multiply it times 10 by entering *10 there,
and then pressing the Tab key, and we get 5400 points.
And that is, by the way, if you do the math,
five feet wide by six and a quarter feet tall.
All right, now I'm gonna press Control + 0
or Command + 0 on a Mac to zoom out
so you can get a sense of how much bigger this artwork is,
and then I'll press the Escape key in order
to return control to the black arrow tool.
Now press Control + A or Command + A on a Mac
to select all of the artwork, and I'll click
on the word Transform up here in the control panel,
or you may see a W and H value instead,
depending on the width of your screen.
And I'm gonna make sure both the width
and height values are locked into alignment with each other,
and I'll click on the W to select that value
and I'll change it to 3800 points,
and then I'll press the Enter key
or the Return key on the Mac to apply that change.
And we now have what is by any standard
this massive piece of artwork that would have been
very difficult to draw in the first place.
I don't see how it would have come up with
these gestures at all if I were trying to draw
something that's actually taller than I am.
And yet, if I press Control + 1 or Command + 1 on a Mac,
in order to zoom in to 100%, you can see
that we have this wonderful detail
that we could not achieve in any other way.
All right, and just as a finishing touch here,
I decided I wanted to thicken up the lines a little bit
for the sake of, let's just say my signature,
and so I press Control + A once again,
Command + A on the Mac to select all the artwork,
I press Control + H or Command + H on a Mac
just to hide those anchor points,
and then I went ahead and changed the line weight
up here in the control panel to two points
in order to thicken things ever so slightly.
And because by default the stroke is centered,
we're actually only adding one point of weight
to either side of any given line.
And that's how you turn a simple piece of line art
from the year 1986, a year before Illustrator
had even hit the market, into a massive piece
of vector-based artwork here inside Illustrator.
【本字幕由CGSUB.COM独家制作发布】
【www.cgsub.com】