Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
Exclusive for http://UKsubtitles.ru
Hello?
Oh, my...
It smells like this room
has not been cleaned
for five whole seasons...
of a television show.
Oh! Hello chicken!
Ooh, your chair so dirty.
If I clean you no run
away, okay?
You promise?
I like you, Chicken.
Oh man! I just realized
they'll probably show
the Sex and the City 3 trailer!
Why are you so excited?
I tried to drag you
to the last one
and you almost
broke up with me.
The last one flopped pretty bad,
so the studio's
making the third one
more guy-friendly.
Well, the lack of testes
was making me testy
but this boring event just took
a sperm for the better.
Hey everyone, this chick is
giving me some...
ah you know what,
it's too easy.
Joke withdrawn, everyone.
Joke withdrawn.
"The detective said Samantha's
collar was rigged to blow
as soon as she made a sex pun.
So it couldn't have been on her
for more than 60 seconds."
Carrie, come
to Miranda's, quick!
The collar was rigged to blow as
soon as she tasted tuna.
Ironically, she was making
an actual tuna fish sandwich.
Mr. Big, someone
is killing my friends!
You've got to help us!
Carrie, I have two secrets.
First, my real name isn't
Alexander Big.
My second secret...
is THIS.
Out of the way gaybies!
Hyah! Hyah!
Big? I feel so strange.
Your brain is getting used to
your new body, Miss Bradshaw.
Uhh, what shall I do
with her old body?
Donate it to science.
Shut up! The Katherine Heigl
movie is starting.
Sex and The City 3!
Shhh!!
Hey hey hey! I avoid starvation
for another day!
Sorry Yogi,
but if you steal
one more basket, it's my job.
You'll never catch me, I live
the life of the free!
Not this time, Yogi.
Ho Chi Hacharu!
Quite the surprise, but try
this one on for size!
Hey, hey, hey!
♪ Go, Go!
Power Forest Rangers ♪
♪ Go, go!
♪ Go, Go!
Power Forest Rangers ♪
What the fuck is happening!!
And that is how you bring
Yogi Bear to Japan!
You're welcome!
They called me mad,
but I did it!
Egypt shall forevermore be known
as the land of giant boobies!
Haha. They're like giant
boobies!
Don't be an idiot!
I just don't think
we're ready for this.
Not-not right now.
Okay.
I understand. It's okay.
Are you on your way
to a fancy party?!
That was my line from our first
appearance on this show.
Eyegorp!
I deserve it!
Oh, man.
You seem so RUTHLESS...
time to make you TOOTHLESS!
Mmm, your beak looks ribbed...
for MY pleasure!
Oh! Ow!
That's not half bad actually.
I'm so happy
'cause you are gonna die
GONNA DIE!
No no no!
No, stop!
A drumroll?
It's so suspenseful!
AAAAAAAAAAA!!
What an ironic death!
I'm a CHAMPION!
Looks like SOMEONE'S
been watching
Tony Jaa's The Protector.
L-Looks like someone
just peed
in his Gatchaman boxer shorts!
Whew.
Suck my sleigh balls!
Argh!
My only weakness!
Duh da da da dah dah daaaah!
Bitch. Pudding!
B-b-b-blam!
How do you like this taste
of Bitch Pudding?!
Your momma sure liked it
when she ate it
out of my butthole!
B-Blam! Bitch Pudding!
Blam blam blam blam blam!
Whoooo! Blam!
Blaaaaamm... Ow!
You saved me!
- Have at thee!
My life has value after all!
Ding dang!
This is gonna be one
dilly of a slobberknocker!
These ratings will be glorious.
Let me just get that for you.
I wish I was a bionic chicken.
That would be so cool.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
Exclusive for http://UKsubtitles.ru